MÓNICA LEIRAS

Digital Marketer



PROFILE

I'm a resourceful and creative digital marketing professional specializing in brand marketing, digital advertising, and growth marketing.

My entrepreneurial and professional path has built up my tenacity, resilience, and growth mindset, and I thrive in developing, executing, and optimizing marketing initiatives.

CONTACT

- (+351) 926 647 341
- monicarafaelaleiras@gmail.com
- Pedrouços, Maia Portugal
- www.monicaleiras.com
- in /monicaleiras
- S live:monicaleiras.mr

LANGUAGES

PORTUGUESE	ENGLISH	SPANISH
Native	C1	A1

EXPERIENCE

JUN 2018 - JAN 2020

CREATIVE MARKETING MANAGER @ CREATIVE 70NE

- Set up and optimize KPIs for Google Ads and email marketing campaigns.
- Manage digital marketing channels of clients in Healthcare and Textiles;
- Manage and optimize the digital strategy of an E-Commerce brand;
- Streamline collaboration with influencers and partners;

FEB 2017 - FEB 2018

CO-FOUNDER & CONTENT MANAGER @ FRAMIE

- Bootstrapped the business from idea to company;
- Key role in customer discovery, go-to-market strategy, and product launch;
- Managed alpha/beta tests, with lead generation campaigns and user interviews for UX-focused product iteration;
- Managed content creation and social media strategy.

DEC 2014 - JUN 2018

DIGITAL MARKETER @ MITIC

- Developed this brand and strategy to acquire leads for freelance work;
- Managed and optimized lead generation for clients in the textile industry;
- Worked with E-Commerce clients in setting up and optimizing KPIs;
- Designed key brand assets in digital and print formats;
- Designed, developed and managed client websites with WordPress.

EDUCATION

SET 2015 - OUT 2017

MASTER'S IN INNOVATION AND TECHNOLOGICAL ENTREPRENEURSHIP @ FEUP & FEP

- Start-up and business development;
- Customer discovery/validation, persona analysis, rapid iteration;
- Go-to-market strategy, product/service development, growth marketing.

SET 2012 - JUL 2015

BACHELOR'S IN BIOLOGY @ ECUM

KEY SKILLS

GROWTH MARKETING	•
PPC	•
BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT	•
MARKETING ANALYTICS	•
EMAIL MARKETING	•
BRAND MANAGEMENT	•
WEB & GRAPHIC DESIGN	•

PROJECTS

> MAR - OUT 2017

MASTER THESIS "MOBILE USER ENGAGEMENT: NEW APPS VS MAINSTREAM APPS"

My dissertation focused on strategies for technological companies to reduce user churn and improve the profitability and loyalty of end-users.

> OUT 2016 - MAR 2018

PINKIT - ONLINE STORE

Leveraging my skills in front-end development, startup bootstrapping and digital marketing, I started this E-Commerce project (women's accessories store) to improve my analytical reasoning, focusing on measuring and optimizing E-Commerce metrics.

ACTIVITIES

> WEB SUMMIT 2017

ALPHA STARTUP

I participated in the Alpha Startups program as Framie's Co-Founder and I took this opportunity to improve my networking skills.

> UNIVERSITY STARTUP WORLD CUP

PORTUGAL FINAL & DENMARK SEMI-FINAL

I partook with the Framie team as we won the Portuguese competition and took part in the International semi-final.

> STARTUP PORTO ACCELERATOR 2017

ANJE & INESCTEC

During this 6-month acceleration program, I expanded my startup development and networking skills.

MANAGEMENT IN LOCAL & UNIVERSITY GROUPS

I had the experience of managing different teams and organizing events.

> VOLUNTARY WORK

Social responsibility has always been a must for me, and I actively collaborate with local and national associations, both in communication and organizing activities.

> SOCIAL ACTIVITIES

I explore my passion for music by directing, training, and playing the organ in a local choir and my passion for acting by being a part of a local theatre group.

TOOLS

GOOGLE ADS	•
GOOGLE ANALYTICS	•
GOOGLE TAG MANAGER	•
DATA STUDIO	•
FACEBOOK ADS	•
WORDPRESS	•
MAILCHIMP	•
E-GOI	•
OMNISEND	•
BUFFER	•
ADOBE PHOTOSHOP	•
ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR	•
ADOBE INDESIGN	•
HUBSPOT	•
GOOGLE OPTIMIZE	•
UBERSUGGEST	•
ADOBE AFTER EFFECTS	•
FILMORA	•

COURSES

> DIGITAL MARKETING

@ GOOGLE (IN-PERSON)

> INBOUND

@ HUBSPOT ACADEMY

> CONTENT MARKETING

@ HUBSPOT ACADEMY

> ANALYTICS AND DATA MASTERY

@ DIGITAL MARKETER LAB

GOOGLE TAG MANAGER FUNDAMENTALS

@ ANALYTICS MANIA